#### Contact

brenton.snyder84@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/brentonsnyder-69ba9453 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Nursing ACLS Hospitals

#### Certifications

Articulate Studio Advanced Techniques

# **Brenton Snyder**

Regional Vice President Clinical Quality and Compliance at Altus Community Health System

Rosharon, Texas

## Summary

Regional Vice President of Clinical Quality and Compliance with over twelve years of practical experience in ER, ICU, nursing leadership, and nursing education settings. Responsible for professional development of clinical staff, regulatory compliance, accreditation, quality, and risk management. Successful in providing vision, leveraging strategic relationships, and building teams. Skillful and knowledgeable about quality assurance, performance improvement, and change management while collaborating with multiple departments to implement system-wide initiatives.

## Experience

Altus Health

Regional Vice President Clinical Quality and Compliance January 2020 - Present (5 months)

Houston, Texas Area

Responsible for quality, compliance, education, patient experience, risk management, policies and procedures, document control, infection control, and accreditation for Altus Community Health System. Working to integrate and standardize processes and procedures throughout the system.

Neighbors Emergency Center Director of Education and Compliance May 2016 - January 2020 (3 years 9 months)

Pearland, TX - Corporate

As Director of Clinical Education I oversee a team of Clinical Educators who are responsible for all education delivered to clinical staff throughout the company. We also collaborate on physician education, leadership education, and corporate employee professional development. The education team has a strong quality and regulatory focus and helps the company maintain compliance through frequent site visits. We provide on-boarding education, annual competencies, in-services, eLearning, new center opening training, and any education needed for roll-outs of new products or processes.

Harris Health System 6 years 6 months

Nursing Instructor November 2013 - April 2016 (2 years 6 months)

Nursing Practice and Professional Advancement

This position focused on system-wide nursing competency. I created and maintained numerous nursing competency computer-based training modules. I created modules and loaded them into a Learning Management System (LMS) using a software called Articulate. I also taught Leadership Development classes, such as a "Charge Nurse Class". Additionally, I assisted with the Graduate Nurse Internship Program at the Harris Health System.

Nursing Clinical Manager - ER February 2012 - November 2013 (1 year 10 months) Ben Taub General Hospital

As a Nursing Clinical Manager in the Ben Taub Emergency Center I was responsible for the operation of the unit while on duty. I also had 36 direct reports and oversaw almost 200 employees. I performed evaluations, scheduling, team building, counselings, coaching, quality audits, and additional managerial responsibilities.

Registered Nurse - ER November 2009 - February 2012 (2 years 4 months) Ben Taub General Hospital

As a staff nurse in the Ben Taub Emergency Center I cared for high acuity patients in a fast paced environment. I served as a trauma nurse, charge nurse, preceptor, and triage nurse. At this Level 1 Trauma center I experienced caring for patients with a wide range of complaints.

## UTMB

Clinical Instructor
January 2012 - January 2015 (3 years 1 month)
School of Nursing

As a Clinical Instructor I supervised 10-20 nursing students while they were in the clinical arena. Some groups were precepted and others were cohorted. I rounded on the nursing students, assessed their knowledge of their patients, and held post-conferences.

St. Luke's Episcopal Health System Registered Nurse - ER

April 2008 - October 2009 (1 year 7 months)

#### **UTMB**

Registered Nurse - MICU June 2006 - April 2008 (1 year 11 months)

## Education

University of Alabama in Huntsville

Doctor of Nursing Practice, Nursing Administration · (2014 - 2018)

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston

Master of Science in Nursing, Executive Nursing Leadership (2010 - 2013)

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston Bachelor of Science (BS), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2004 - 2006)

Lamar University · (2002 - 2004)